JOSE MARTOS

FRONT-END ENGINEER

TECH STACK

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, CSS-in-JS ES6+, React, Vue.js, jQuery, TypeScript, Jest, Node.js, Express

Next.js, Webpack, Parcel, Gulp, Babel, ESlint, Prettier, PostCSS

RWD, Page optimisation, SEO JIRA, Git(flow), GitLab, Docker

COURSES

- Digital Product Design (20h | 2020)
- React 16.8 (10h | 2019)
- Javascript testing practises and principles (5h | 2019)
- API design in Node.js (4h | 2019)
- Web performance (5h | 2019)
- Typescript 3 (5h | 2019)
- Photoshop CS5 (80h | 2012)
- Systems & Networks (534h | 2006)

TOOLS

- Figma, InVision, Photoshop
- VS Code, WebStorm, Sublime Text
- Sequel Pro, HeidiSQL, Compass

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: C1 | German: B1

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Trekking, Traveling, Reading, Photography, Martial arts

CONTACT

martosjosele@gmail.com Based in Munich 10.07.1987 – Málaga, Spain github.com/josemartos

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Developer with a focus on efficiency and **minimalism**, and an eye for good **design**. I am eager for new experiences, a **creative** problem solver, and fast learner. When working, I value code **quality**, sense of humour, **team-work**, reliability, and proactivity. I am happy to live in a time with great tools and frameworks to assist **people** in building applications better and faster.

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Front-end Engineer & Junior Designer

Flyla GmbH - Munich (Nov 2019 - May 2020)

- Developed new features on the platform. Refactored the code to diminish the technical debt. Worked with *React / Redux, TS and Styled Components*
- Improved the look and feel of the site with a minimal approach using Figma
- Won the 1st prize at the IATA AIR *Hackathon* celebrated in Seattle, Feb 2020 "Best booking experience"

Front-end Engineer

Pantaflix GmbH - Berlin (Mar 2017 - Sep 2018)

- Implemented a web app tool for the customer care department using *Vue.js*, responsible for the set-up with *Webpack* and further development
- Responsible for the front-end on a CMS for filmmakers and consumers, using plain *JavaScript* and Twig. Microservice architecture oriented
- Implemented new features on the main website, using jQuery and Node.js

Front-end Developer

Team2Venture GmbH - Berlin (Oct 2014 - Feb 2017)

- Participated in a white-label CMS for external companies to handle freelancers and projects, using plain *JavaScript* and Scala templates
- Implemented new features on the main website using {\it Backbone}, participating on a migration from RequireJS to {\it Browserify} + {\it Gulp}

Full-stack Developer

Dreamsite - Madrid (Jun 2012 - Sep 2014)

- Developed +10 corporation websites using *jQuery* and PHP
- Integrated designs in Wordpress pages

Junior Full-stack Developer & UI Designer

Uniagro SL - Málaga (Jul 2009 - May 2012)

- Designed and developed +15 corporation websites using *jQuery* and PHP
- Designed logos and banners

EDUCATION

Senior Technician in Computer Applications Development (2007 - 2009) IES Pedro Espinosa, Antequera, Málaga